RARES COSTIN MUNTEANU

SOFTWARE ENGINEER +40763277778

• DETAILS •

+40763277778 raresmunteanu29@yahoo.com

LINKS

Linkedin

SKILLS

Git

Python

Web Crawling

MongoDB

Flask

SQL

ΑI

Neural Networks

Computer Networking

Cyber Security

REST

Machine Learning

Web Development

fastAPI

Pytest

HOBBIES

Basketball Aikido Guitar playing Smartphones

LANGUAGES

English

German

PROFILE

Passionate Software Engineer with almost 5 years of experience in Cyber Security domain with implications mainly in vulnerability processing components.

I respond to challenges and I am open to always learn new things and improve projects i work with.

I am characterized by perseverance and the power of concentration. I am also a sociable person, who likes to interact with teammates both professionally and socially.

■ EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Python Developer at Lionstep, Remote

September 2022 — Present

- Implicated into the process of re-architecture and rewriting of the entire product in Python with fast API(mainly written in ruby rails)
- Created a new feature for the product to find similarities between jobs(machine learning knowledge involved)
- CI/CD flows for automatic testing and deployment to google cloud
- · Written tests for API integration with pytest

Software Engineer at Bitdefender, lasi

May 2018 — August 2022

- Designed and developed API that is used to correlate vulnerabilities with products installed on endpoints. This component plays a key role and represents over 60 % of Vulnerabilities Detection process.
- Designed and developed tool that will be used to identify critical resources in
 a company. This component will be a big part in prioritizing security measures
 taken on company endpoints. This project will use and correlate information from
 millions of endpoints. This project is based on my Computer Science Degree.
- Designed and developed a component that creates an internet surfing profiling and
 retrieves a risk score for each user. The amount of data that is processed is of the
 order of billions entries each week. This component will have a great impact on
 endpoints and companies at vulnerability assessment level.
- Designed and developed a component that process multiple feeds from NVD(National Vulnerability Database) to construct correlations between cpes and cves. There are 3 feeds, that contains millions of entries that need to be processed. This database is the core of vulnerability detection process and represents 100% of the vulnerabilities information owned.
- Designed, developed and maintained over 5 crawlers used to extract and manipulate different types of data.
- Research in vulnerability field. From this research, over 200 risk indicators were created that played a big role in vulnerability detection components.
- Most of the components presented above implies working with big flow of data, mainly non relational databases (MongoDB) and modules used for API design (Flask).
- Maintaining different projects that implied working with virtual machines, different rdp connections, etc. This projects are part of Vulnerability Assessment also.

Teaching Assistant at Faculty of Computer Science Iasi, Iasi

October 2020 — October 2022

 Responsible for teaching Python Programming subject laboratory classes to 3rd year students. That implies teaching, resolving problems with students and answer to a variety of questions. This experience not only improved my speech and the ability to speak in front of
other peoples, specially new ones, but also made me realize how many things i
need to learn and improve. The teaching act means a a perpetual work that is the
base for mastering a domain.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Faculty of Computer Science, lasi

October 2020 — July 2022

Specialization: Computational Optimization.

Grade: 9.50

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Faculty of Computer Science, lasi

October 2017 — July 2020

Finished Computer Science Faculty with final grade 9.25.